Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/n-s-m-rezaur-rahman-b1b59410b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs)

Large Language Models (LLM) NumPy

Languages

Bengali (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Convolutional Neural Networks Structuring Machine Learning Projects

Sample-based Learning Methods Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning

Sequence Models

Honors-Awards

Dean's Gold Medal
Best Senior Engineer of 2022

Publications

Oboyob: A sequential-semantic Bengali image captioning engine

Improvement of the performance of optical handwritten digit recognition by incorporating cross-domain autoencoder-based image to image translation technique

Selection of most suitable secondary school alternative by multi-criteria fuzzy analytic hierarchy process

Fusion of BWM and AHP MCDM Methods to Choose the Most Suitable Secondary School for an Individual in the Context of Bangladesh

N.S.M. Rezaur Rahman

Principal Software Engineer (AI) at BJIT Dhaka, Bangladesh

Summary

A passionate AI researcher with more than six years of experience in doing research and developing AI systems with python. I have extensive experience on planning, designing and developing Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing and Recommender System models. During my career I have also been awarded with a best senior engineer of the year award. Hardwork, patience and honesty - which I believe to be the key of all my success in life.

Experience

BJIT

5 years 2 months

Principal Software Engineer
July 2024 - Present (1 year 1 month)
Bangladesh

Senior Software Engineer July 2021 - September 2024 (3 years 3 months)

Bangladesh

Software Engineer

June 2020 - June 2021 (1 year 1 month)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

University of Information Technology and Sciences Lecturer

January 2017 - April 2020 (3 years 4 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

I had an experience of working as a lecturer in the department of Computer Science & Engineering. My responsibilities were - teaching & research.

Education

North South University

Master of Science - MS, Computer Science and Engineering · (January 2018 - June 2019)

University of Information Technology and Sciences Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2012 - 2016)